Privacy Policy  

=================

### 1\. Overview

ServiceM8 is field service management software for trade contractors and home services businesses. It’s cloud-based Software as a Service (SaaS). Field staff use the software via a native app for iPhone, iPad and Apple Watch, and office staff can access the ServiceM8 dashboard via web browser on their Mac or PC.  

ServiceM8 is committed to maintaining the privacy of your personal information.  
  
The primary purpose of this policy is to communicate to you how ServiceM8 deals with your personal information. It explains how we collect, use and disclose your personal information, as well as other information or data associated with you and your use of our services. It also informs you about rights and responsibilities you have regarding your personal information, in association with your use of our services.  

We believe in informed consent at ServiceM8. We therefore encourage you to read this policy carefully, to help you make an informed decision about sharing your information with us.  

By accessing or using our website or software, you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy as well as our [Terms of Service](https://www.servicem8.com/terms-of-service).  

#### Defined terms

* “You” & “Your”: “You” may be a visitor to one of our websites, or a new or existing user of our Service.
* “ServiceM8”, “we”, “us”, “our”: ServiceM8 Pty Ltd & its affiliates.
* “Service”: our Software as a Service for field service management, available via a native app for iPhone, iPad and Apple Watch, and web browser, as well as all subsidiary or additional services offered and controlled by ServiceM8 through use of your account.

‍

This policy does not apply to third-party websites, products, or services even if they link to our Services, and You should consider the privacy practices and policies of those third parties carefully.  

If You disagree with the practices described in this policy, You should (a) take the necessary steps to remove cookies from Your computer after leaving our website, and (b) discontinue Your use of our Services. Note ServiceM8's [Cookie Policy](https://www.servicem8.com/cookie-policy) describes how we use cookies and similar technologies.

‍

### 2\. Information We Collect

ServiceM8 collects personal, business and non-identifiable information about You. This privacy policy is primarily concerned with how we deal with Your personal information.  

Personal information is information that can be used to identify an individual person, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, contact information or address.

‍

#### Personal information

We may collect personal information, and other information, when You:  

* ‍Register to use the Service
* ‍Demo or trial the Service
* Use the Service, on any device
* Communicate with us
* Visit our website
* Post to our blog
* Like or interact with us on social media  

When you create a ServiceM8 account, we may ask for and collect personal information, such as Your:  

* Name
* Email
* Address
* Phone number/s
* Staff names, email addresses, and phone numbers  

This personal information is voluntarily provided, and can be edited and updated in the settings of your account with the Service. You may choose not to provide some of Your personal information, however this may prevent or severely constrain our ability to provide You with the Service and/or Your ability to use the Service.

‍

#### End-customer personal information

If you’re a customer of one of our users, the user will likely need to collect information about you when you interact with the user's business through the ServiceM8 Service. For example, if you initiate a transaction with the user through the ServiceM8 Service & their use of the ServiceM8 service, such as booking a job, the user may collect information about you, such as your name, address, phone number/s, email, as well as other information you provide for the purpose of the dealings or transaction.

‍

If you believe a ServiceM8 user has entered your personal information into their ServiceM8 account, you will need to contact that ServiceM8 user directly regarding any questions or requests you have around the storage, use and retention of your information.  
‍

If you use ServiceM8 Messenger, view the separate Privacy & Terms [here](https://www.servicem8.com/messenger-privacy-terms).

‍

#### Other information

We may also automatically collect non-personal information that Your computer or mobile device provides to us in connection with Your visit to our website, communication with us, or trial or use of the Service, such as:

‍

* Type of computer or mobile device
* Device operating system
* Unique device identifier
* Browser type
* Browsing activity
* IP Address
* MAC address
* Physical location (including geolocation, beacon based location, and/or GPS location)

‍

You may disable our use of certain location data through Your device or browser settings, for example by disabling “Location Services” for the ServiceM8 App in iOS privacy settings. We may also store usage data such as the date and time the application on your device accesses our servers, and what information and files have been downloaded to the application based on your device number.

‍

#### Special categories of data 

ServiceM8 does not knowingly attempt to solicit or receive special categories of data, such as personal information relating to race, ethnic origin, political association, trade union membership, religious beliefs, criminal records or health information.

‍  

### 3\. How Information May Be Used

ServiceM8 collects Your personal information so that we can provide You with the Service and any related services You request. In doing so, ServiceM8 may use the personal information we have collected from You for purposes related to the Service, including to:  

* Provide the Service to You, including any additional features, ‘Add-ons’ or connections You activate as part of your use of the Service
* Respond to Your enquiries and requests
* Administer our provision of the Service to You
* Identify You as a User in our system
* Verify Your identity
* Communicate with You in provision of technical support and any other issues You might experience in using the Service
* Send You training, marketing or promotional communications, related to the Service
* Send You information important to Your use of the Service, such as changes to our terms, conditions and policies
* Seek feedback from You in the interest of improving our services, including for the purpose of seeking a testimonial or completing a client survey
* Aggregate personal and other information into non-identifiable, anonymous data to help improve our Services
* Enforce our Terms of Service & policies
* Facilitate our internal business operations, including the fulfilment of any legal requirements
* Prosecute or defend in a court, arbitration, or similar legal proceeding

‍

Your use of the Service means You consent to the collection, holding and usage of personal and other information for these purposes, and any other purpose for which you have provided express permission, on an ongoing basis until termination of Your use of the Service, subject to the terms of this policy and our Terms of Service.  

### 4\. How We Disclose Data

ServiceM8 is committed to the confidentiality of your information and account data, and will only disclose Your personal and other information to third parties for limited purposes relating to provision of the Service to You, for the improvement of our Service, and under certain circumstances, as described below. We may disclose Your personal and other information with:  

* **ServiceM8 affiliates**: we may disclose Your information to entities that we control, for their internal business purposes and as part of our provision of the Service to You.  
    ‍
* **Third party service providers**: we may disclose Your information or account data to third party service providers for the purpose of providing You with the Service, improving our Service, and other aforementioned purposes for how we use Your information, including services such as website hosting, data analysis, payment processing services, information technology and related infrastructure provision, customer service, email delivery, SMS/text delivery, credit card processing, auditing, phone communications, and other similar services. These third parties include but are not limited to: Amazon Web Services, BulkSMS, Clickatell, ClickSend, FullStory, Google, LiveChat, Mailchimp, Mixpanel, Nexmo, OpenAI, PartnerStack, Postmark, Slack, Stripe, Twilio and Zendesk.  
    ‍
* **Your customers**: we may disclose Your information, and Your ServiceM8 staff information, to Your customers as part of our provision and Your use of the Service. For example, ServiceM8 sends emails and text messages from You and Your staff to Your customers, which may contain personal and other information.  
    ‍
* **Authorised third-parties**, such as when You connect Your ServiceM8 account to a third-party ‘Add-on’ e.g. organisations like accounting packages (Xero, QuickBooks Online, and MYOB) or timesheet solutions like Deputy. The use of Your personal data by an authorised third party is subject to the third party’s privacy policy.  
    ‍
* **Independent ServiceM8 Partners** which You have agreed to, sought or requested contact with for the purpose of ServiceM8 consultation, training and setup.  
    ‍
* **Law enforcement agencies, legal systems and regulatory authorities**: we may be required to disclose Your information, without Your consent, in order to comply with any court orders, subpoenas, or other legal processes or investigations, if such disclosure is required by law. Where possible and appropriate, we will notify You if we are required by law to disclose Your personal information.  
    ‍
* **Successors**: we may disclose Your information in the case of a sale, merger, consolidation, liquidation, reorganisation, or acquisition. In that event, any acquirer will be subject to the obligations of this privacy policy.  
    ‍
* **People browsing our message boards, chat, profile pages, blogs and other services** to which You are able to post information and materials, including “Testimonials, Ratings and Reviews” and “Public Forum.” If You submit or agree to testimonials, ratings or reviews to the Service, any Personal Information You include will be displayed in the Service. If you want Your testimonial removed, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.servicem8.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).  
    ‍
* Your contacts associated with your social media accounts, ServiceM8’s social media contacts, and browsers of the applicable social media, in connection with any of Your social media activity related to ServiceM8.  
    ‍
* Any other entity for which You have provided express consent for disclosure of Your information.

‍

### 5\. Security

ServiceM8 takes reasonable physical, technical and administrative precautions to protect Your information from loss, theft, or unauthorised access, alteration or disclosure.  

ServiceM8's servers are secured by SSL Certificates issued by Amazon, so all data transferred between You and ServiceM8 is encrypted, including data transferred to iPhone and iPad devices.  

ServiceM8 is built from the ground up using Amazon's Cloud Computing technology. Your account data is backed up every 24 hours to Amazon's S3 infrastructure in multiple locations around the world. Data is redundantly stored on multiple devices across multiple facilities in an Amazon S3 Region (note this multi-region service is not available if You are located within the European Economic Area).

‍

#### Notification of breach

Should ServiceM8 become aware of any accidental, unauthorised or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, disclosure, or breach of personal information, if such a breach represents a risk to the rights and freedoms of natural persons, ServiceM8 will notify You of the breach as soon as possible.

#### Username & password security

It is your responsibility to protect the security of your ServiceM8 username and password. ServiceM8 staff, and independent ServiceM8 Partners, do not have access to your password and will never ask for your password. Your ServiceM8 password should be unique.

‍

### 6\. Advertising & Choice

ServiceM8 will not sell or otherwise disclose Your information to marketers or promotional third parties without your consent.  

ServiceM8 may use your information for the purpose of sending you training, marketing or promotional communications, related to the Service, or which we determine may be of interest to you due to being relevant to Your business or industry.  

You may opt out of these communications via ‘unsubscribe’ mechanisms. However, note that we may still send You communications important to Your use and our provision and administration of the Service to You.

‍

### 7\. Access to Your Information & Retention of Information

You may access your information via Your ServiceM8 account or through a request to us.  

You have the ability to access, alter or correct Your personal information within Your ServiceM8 account. It is Your responsibility to ensure the personal information You provide us is complete, accurate and up to date.

You can request, at no charge, all personal and other information we hold about you in writing at [\[email protected\]](https://www.servicem8.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Following an information request, if you believe any of the information we hold about you is unnecessary, inaccurate, out of date or incomplete, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.servicem8.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

To request removal of Your personal information from any websites or forums controlled by ServiceM8, please request this in writing through [\[email protected\]](https://www.servicem8.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) .

We will process Your requests as soon as reasonably practicable. If it is not reasonable, practical, or appropriate for us to process Your request in the manner you have requested, or we determine it to be frivolous or vexatious, we will advise you accordingly.  

You may access a backup of all data within Your ServiceM8 account once every 24 hours (in your Online Dashboard, go to Settings > Backup).

You may close Your ServiceM8 account at any time. This will terminate Your access to the Service and result in the immediate deletion or anonymization of your account data, including historic backups, stored in various locations around the world. However, note that ServiceM8 may have a variety of obligations to retain some or all of Your personal and other information for certain periods.

‍

### 8\. Use of Services by Minors

You may not use the Service if you are under 16 years of age, unless ServiceM8 is provided with the appropriate parental or legal guardian consent.

### 9\. International Transfers

Our services are global and account data (including Your personal and other information) may be stored and processed in any country where we have operations or where we engage service providers, and we may transfer Your information to countries outside of Your country of residence, which may have data protection rules that are different to those of Your country. In these cases we will take measures to ensure that any such transfers, and Your information and account data, remain protected.

‍

If You are located within the European Economic Area (EEA), your account data will be housed in data centres within the EEA. Note that certain personal information and account data may still be transferred outside of the EEA for the purpose of provision of the Service to You. In these cases, ServiceM8 has taken measures to ensure such transfers are provided an adequate level of protection and remain in accordance with applicable data protection law. You can read about ServiceM8 & the EU's _General Data Protection Regulation_ [here](https://www.servicem8.com/gdpr).  

### 10\. Responsibilities for processing and controlling personal information

Through provision of the Service to You, ServiceM8 has an obligation to process Your personal and other information, and account data, as directed by You as part of Your use of the Service, and in accordance with this policy and our Terms of Service. Under this policy and as a data controller, ServiceM8 has certain obligations to ensure the privacy of Your personal and other information.

In turn, Your use of the Service involves You collecting, holding and using certain personal and other information about Your customers and any other personal data. You determine and control the entry, use and retention of any personal information within your account. You should be aware of Your responsibilities as a data controller when collecting, holding and using personal information about Your customers, and the corresponding rights of Your customers or data subjects.

‍

If You collect, hold and use a third party's personal information as part of Your use of the Service then You warrant to us that You have the third party’s consent to do so.

###   
11\. Updates to this Privacy Policy and Notifications

ServiceM8 reserves the right to change this policy at any time, and any amended policy is effective upon the posting on this website. In the event of any significant update/s, ServiceM8 will communicate these changes to You via email, notification via the website, or notification through Your account.

You agree that electronic disclosures and notices have the same meaning and effect as if we had provided You with hard copy disclosures. Disclosures and notices in relation to this policy or Your information shall be considered to be received by You within 24 hours of the time they are posted to our website or sent to You via email or notification through Your account.

‍

### Contact Us

If You have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy or how your personal information is handled, please contact our Privacy Officer at [\[email protected\]](https://www.servicem8.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

‍

If you are dissatisfied with our handling of a query or request raised under this privacy policy, you may consider submitting a complaint to your country's data protection authority.

‍

Last updated: March 2023  

### Features

### Industries

### Resources

### Company

 | 

 | 

© 2024 ServiceM8™ | Smart Job Management

Region
